

Webb Lu

PHP Programmer

Kaohsiung, Taiwan

u.master.o.twn@gmail.com

https://uwaylu.github.io/blog

中文, English, 台語

BACKGROUND

ABOUT

高雄人,碼農。

大學時研究過 PHP 爬蟲,獲取手機論壇的討論文章; 碩班期間以 matlab 協作模擬 LTE-A 網路的資源分配;

2016年8月時任職於新裕豐文化事業,工作範圍涉及後端的PHP到前端的Javascript;隨著時間推移接觸了各種技術後,越期盼能夠團隊式的開發並進行討論、互相砥礪,工作環境中能夠在同領域互相交流。

閒暇時,2017 上半年目標是「建立個人部落格,分享 Evernote 筆記」, 期間在 OpenShift 上架設了 wordpress、 摸索了 Laravel, Vuejs 與 axios(基於 promise 的 ajax libs)等各種新知, 最後情定 github.io 與 jekyll 靜態部落格生成器。

AFK 時喜歡與好友喝飲料談天,或騎單車四處走走; 17年2月完成了高雄-墾丁百里騎乘,7月完成了左營單車挑戰百里。

18-19 年習慣於舒適圈,慶幸部落格還是在 20 年基於 vuepress 上到 github。 半年目標是慢慢整理 Notion 上的筆記,發布到部落格。

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep, 2017 - Aug, 2020

配合專案管理者協作完成需求,並撰寫文件

- API 對接整合 (slim 3, eloquent 5)
- 整合系統管理界面 (vue 2, nuxt 2, vuetify)
- 。 開發環境使用 docker; 部署到 VM

PHP Programmer, 新裕豐文化事業

Aug, 2016 - Aug, 2017 1 year

- 。 引入 Codelgniter 3 framework, 全站重構、優化暨靜態化除錯
- o 結合各種新知,後端 API 與前端 Vue 雙向繫結實現新購物車開發
- 。 以 piax 實現良好體驗的搜尋功能
- o 最新商品全站架構與實現(後台 Excel 快速上架,拖曳上船商品圖,自動生成 xml 格式 sitemap,採用中 文網址等)
- o 後台商品維護相關功能:批次指定類目跟隨特定商品牌價、匯出商品資料成 Excel 檔案
- 。 於測試機架設 Gogs 提供公司做版本控制

SKILLS



EDUCATION

工程科學所,,國立成功大學

Aug, 2012 - Jul, 2016

數學暨資訊教育學系, Bachelor, 國立臺北教育大學

Aug, 2008 - Jul, 2012

,,國立鳳山高中

Aug, 2006 - Jul, 2008

AWARDS

第五屆全國大專校院資安技能金盾潛力無窮獎 資策會

Awarded on: Dec 10, 2010

隊名:「不要抓我拜託」

VOLUNTEER WORK

PHP backend, Mobile Open Platform Conference

May, 2018 - Nov, 2012

官網後端協助;年會攤位工作人員

Guide, Third IEEE International Conference on Smart Grid Communications

Nov, 2012 - Nov, 2012

Guide researchers and participants from all over the country to the auditorium.

宣傳股股長,國立臺北教育大學數學暨資訊教育學系系學會

Aug, 2010 - Jul, 2011

與系學會各股協作,並與股員共同宣傳系學會主辦之活動等相關事宜。

PUBLICATIONS

Uplink Scheduling and Power Allocation for M2M Communications in SC-FDMA-Based LTE-A Networks With QoS Guarantees, IEEE

Published on: Jul 01, 2017

Providing diverse and strict quality-of-service (QoS) guarantees is one of the most important requirements in machine-to-machine (M2M) communications, which is particularly need for appropriate resource allocation for a large number of M2M devices. To efficiently allocate resource blocks (RBs) for M2M devices while satisfying QoS requirements, we propose group-based M2M communications, in which M2M devices are clustered based on their wireless transmission protocols, their QoS characteristics, and their requirements. To perform joint RB and power allocation in SC-FDMA-based LTE-A networks, we formulate a sum-throughput maximization problem, while respecting all the constraints associated with SC-FDMA scheme, as well as QoS requirements in M2M devices. The constraints in uplink SC-FDMA air interface in LTE-A networks complicate the resource allocation problem. We solve the resource allocation problem by first transforming it into a binary integer programming problem and then formulate a dual problem using the Lagrange duality theory. Numerical results show that the proposed algorithm outperforms traditional Greedy algorithm in terms of throughput maximization while satisfying QoS requirements, and its performance is close to the optimal design.

INTERESTS

Programming Hello, World! Sports Bike Riding Jogging

Games

RPG MMORPG DOTA

Others

Music Anime